Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
This is the Yamato's current location.
And our next warp will take us out of the galaxy.
41 kiloparsecs separate our galaxy and the Large Magellanic Cloud.
In other words, we still have 130,000 light years of unknown space ahead.
Once we're beyond the Milky Way,
our enemy will stop pursuing us so closely.
Why do you say that?
That's...
When you consider the conditions required for civilization...
That is, the number of available systems,
it's likely the Garmillas System exists within our own galaxy.
Come to think of it, you're right.
Either way, it'll be good to have the Garmillans off our backs for a while.
You're so relaxed... You amaze me.
What do you mean?
I'm saying that you shouldn't be taking it so easy.
Wait a second.
What makes you think I'm taking it easy?
You're being stupidly idealistic.
Are you talking about Melda?
She's a Garmillan!
That has nothing to do with this.
So you believe what she said, don't you? That we fired first!
When did I say that?
Well, you basically said so!
Calm down, guys.
You shut up!
Be quiet, you fools!
Your blood pressure's a little high.
I'll keep an eye out.
I heard about it.
The young ones lose their tempers easily.
You have to control yourself, too.
You always know what I'm thinking.
Curse that old man...
"You lack the self-awareness required of an officer."
This is what they do to punish elementary school children.
Let's finish this up and hit the next one.
I'm done.
They're offering a limited-time Milky Way lunch in the cafeteria. Want to try it?
Honestly...
I see. So you told Shima.
Yes.
Then that's what had him so upset.
Do you regret it?
No, he was Captain Daigo Shima's son. He'll accept the truth.
That is what I believe.
You really think so? People in high positions can be surprisingly fragile.
I'll be off, then.
I see.
Thank you. It's a big help.
You're welcome. Please excuse me.
Please wait.
His Lordship is using the hotline right now.
The hotline?
Out of the way.
But...
Out of the way!
It seems I misunderstood.
I thought you'd gone back to your old tricks out of pity for them.
You are my country's heart and soul. Naturally, I'm worried.
Peace in the universe is only possible because of our friendship.
Yes?
Next I'd like to speak to you in person. We'll talk again some other time.
What brings you two here?
Preparations for Senior General Domel's medal ceremony have been completed.
Very well. What about you, Gimleh?
I've come to report the secret police's latest findings.
Regarding the rogue elements within the empire.
I shall leave this to you. Handle it in any way you wish.
I will take care of it.
More importantly...
That is the Terron ship, yes?
Where are they heading?
What is the end of their journey?
It appears we've found out.
Ghale Domel!
Ghale Domel! Ghale Domel!
Stop the car.
General!
Thank you.
Ghale Domel! Ghale Domel!
Ghale Phuzeron!
You're perhaps wondering why
I've recalled you from the front lines.
The Small Magellanic Cloud is the lynchpin of our defenses.
The absence of a commanding officer aids the enemy.
There has been a problem within the Milky Way Theatre.
I've heard the rumors. A Terron ship broke through our dragnet.
And Schultz fell in battle against them?
I would like for you to take care of this barbarian ship.
Will you go?
If that is your order. I am a soldier, loyal to you and to the Empire.
Hurrah to the shining star of Garmillas!
A promotion to High Chief General?
What concerns me is your popularity among the people.
Be wary. Many of those who surround
His Lordship do not think well of your rise.
Goer, your new direct superior,
is one of Sideburns Zoellik's lackeys.
I'm not interested in politics.
Baleras has changed.
Oh, I was glad to hear your Melda was safe.
My daughter is very inconsiderate. She refuses to share any details.
Do you see that, Elk? Even the fierce Admiral Ditz has a weakness.
Quiet, Talan.
I have a request, Admiral.
Could you lend me that specialized operations ship?
That ship?
Halt.
What's wrong?
Imperial Guard checkpoint. Your identification.
Excuse me.
Has something happened?
Sabotage at the Floating Plant.
What are those?
Rebel forces we found.
They look like ordinary citizens.
It doesn't matter.
Director Gimleh has ordered that they all be sent to the prison planet.
Please pass through. Ghale Desler!
Damn that man.
You were right. Baleras has changed.
You want to be let out here?
Yes.
What we discussed earlier... I'll take care of it.
Thank you.
Are you sure? The Leader's permission is required to use that ship.
I am Supreme Commander of Astrofleets.
I'll pretend I never asked.
The Imperial Marshal continues to expand our territory,
and the Jirel witch spreads his propaganda.
The Vice-Commander is a figurehead, the Guard's arrogance is astonishing,
and our leader...
...plans to move the capital.
To move the capital? To move Baleras?
A great unification.
Where have we come from, and where are we going?
Stop playing the philosopher.
I didn't think you remembered this day.
I'm glad you did.
At our Leader's bequest, I've temporarily returned.
Oh.
Look, it's a rokrhok bird!
Come down here!
If they were alive, they'd be that age now.
What did our leader want?
He ordered me to command the Milky Way Theatre's armies.
Hey!
The Milky Way is far from here.
Yes.
So very far...
It is.
Before long, we shall be one.
Stay there and watch, as the wolf I've released catches its prey in its jaws...
Doctor Sado?
They survived, but it appears they suffer from amnesia...
What a terrible accident.
Rumors say it was terrorism.
Ms. Yuki Mori
Auto-navigation system, all clear.
What's wrong? Have a weird dream?
Yeah. Uh, a dream about a beautiful woman!
If she was beautiful, it was a good dream.
No! No, no, no, wait!
You, too, Hayashi?
Really, it was a beautiful woman.
The auto-navigation room, huh?
It looked just like her!
Overwork.
But they say that the room's haunted.
I wouldn't be surprised if there were a ghost...
It wasn't that kind of ghost.
How am I supposed to know?!
And she was naked...
Don't remove her clothes!
Stop being stupid, drink this, and go to sleep!
Tranquilizer?
She looked just like Mori...
Maybe he should be heading to Niimi instead of us...
Doctor.
I've finished cleaning the patient room.
Oh, good work.
Ensign Yamamoto, you are now released from the brig.
I'm sure it was a rough six days.
Don't do anything else stupid.
We lost a valuable ship...
Your safety is more important.
Yeah, that's how it is.
You finished your punishment?
Yup, everything's shining.
You were playing that again.
Yes, it helps me relax.
Really...
Hey, do you think I'd be able to pilot this like Yamamoto does?
Nope.
What do you mean, "nope"?
You're here because of her, right?
I understand how she feels.
I don't want to believe it, either.
I lost my family to their attacks, too...
And my brother died in battle.
Never knowing he was just a decoy.
Kodai...
Don't look like that. I've settled things in my mind.
Right now, I'll just trust Captain Okita.
But he isn't like me. He has family to protect.
Safe Travels
In that sense, I'm a little jealous.
You can make a new family.
Everyone on this ship is your family.
You're right.
Don't you have a mother and a brother?
My eldest has a wife and child, and then I've another son.
My second son says he wants to be a sailor like me.
A sailor?
Not that there are any ships left.
But isn't it nice anyway?
No, I'm more interested in my grandchild.
She's very cute. I can't die until I find her a good husband.
Won't be easy to find someone who meets your standards...
I know! Why don't you marry her?
Aiko's going to grow up to be a very beautiful lady.
And you can have her!
No, I couldn't...
I'll think about it.
Hey, Shima.
Sometimes there's more than one truth.
You have your truth, and they have theirs.
But there is only one reality. The war really happened.
Even so, you and I have our families.
We are blessed. Don't you think so?
Kodai Susumu, coming in.
Excuse me. This is the final room.
Excellent timing. I was just thinking I wanted to talk to you.
I see, so you're out.
It's been six days.
Why are you holding a mop?
Oh, I suppose the same thing that happened to you.
I disobeyed orders, too.
I opposed the surprise attack, and I was removed from duty.
Is that what happened?
Do you think I was right?
I do.
I disobeyed an order. That isn't what a soldier should do.
Not ever.
But then...
But there are times even a soldier should act like a human being.
People make mistakes.
You need the courage to disobey an order you believe is wrong, to remain true to yourself.
That is what I think.
I understand how you feel.
I believe you wished to avenge your family.
And in the end, the enemy saved me.
Even so, you stayed true to your feelings.
Maybe Kodai was too idealistic when he said we and Melda could understand each other.
However, I understand a little now.
Your father isn't going to fight.
I'm sure we can be friends with the aliens.
She's our enemy. Don't you hate her?
I don't feel hatred anymore.
Really?
Yes, hold on to hope.
A Message from the Yamato Cafeteria
I had time to cool my head.
Limited-Time Special Menu
I see.
Milky Way Lunch
Only ten served per day
Kodai was worried.
I'll be heading up.
Milky Way Lunch
Only ten served per day
Akira... Thank you.
Guess I'll go cool my own head!
How long are they running that limited-time lunch?
Until next week, I think.
I'm free tomorrow.
Okay.
What?
Hit on our port side! A torpedo!
Episode 12
What Lies Beyond
Believe that
Only the future
Has the answer
No one knows
Memory only strikes at
The heart to find
The truth
Do not forget it…
Many stars lie beyond
The spiral of memory
Sparkling in what looks like
The light of memory
The Yamato hides, wounded.
The eyes of a hunter search for it.
The shadow of an invisible enemy, sharpening its fangs.
Is there any way to escape those fangs?
A howl resounds through the emptiness of space.
Next time: The Wolf from Another Dimension.
There are 317 days left before humanity is extinct.